### **TAPAN PATRA**

**R&D** Test Lead

9703811214 • tapankpatro@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/tapan-kumar-patra-4b115824/ • Hyderabad, India

#### Summary

As an experienced tester with over 14 years in agile environments, I excel in crafting effective test strategies, producing meticulous test documentation, executing test cases proficiently, developing robust test data libraries and custom test tools, configuring versatile testing platforms, delivering prompt and comprehensive bug reports, advocating for improved testability, evaluating code quality, conducting API testing, implementing test automation using the C# Stack, utilizing DevOps tooling such as Azure, mastering product knowledge, and deeply understanding user requirement.

#### Key Skills

- \* Test Automation | Testing | Agile Scrum | C# | Python | JavaScript | Selenium | Azure
- Critical Thinking | Team Leadership
- \* AVEVA PDMS | AVEVA ERM | AVEVA Asset Information Management | Industrial Automation

# Experience

AVEVA Hyderabad, India R&D Product Owner 6/2023 – Present

- Leading AVEVA Integration cloud service as a Product Owner, blending technical expertise with agile methodologies for impactful delivery.
- Helped Product Owner to manage and refine the product backlog to create clear and detailed user stories, acceptance criteria, and prioritization, enabling the team to work effectively and deliver valuable features.
- Applied agile methodologies Scrum to help iterative development, conducting regular reviews and demos, gathering stakeholder feedback, and making data-driven adjustments to enhance the product.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including development, design, and marketing, to align on product vision, goals, and development timelines, fostering a cohesive and efficient work environment.
- Functioned as the primary point of contact for internal and external stakeholders, effectively communicating product updates, status, and roadmaps, fostering strong relationships, and ensuring alignment.

AVEVA Hyderabad, India R&D Team Lead 6/2019 – 5/2023

- Leading a team of 4 QA engineers to ensure the delivery of high-quality engineering and industrial automation software in azure cloud.
- · Handle customer communications and understand the business logic and the technical side of the application under test.
- Oversaw the execution of manual and automated test cases, analyzing results and reporting defects to the development team. Collaborate closely with development teams to create effective test strategies and plans. Ensure comprehensive test coverage for all features and functionalities.
- Facilitate team's planning and removing impediments of the team to achieve the sprint goals/deliverables while coaching agile principles.
- Managed and mentored a team of four testers, including resource allocation, task assignments, and performance evaluations, support the onboarding process for new testers at team level.

AVEVA Hyderabad, India R&D Senior Test Engineer 9/2014 - 6/2019

- · Drive the evaluation and adoption of test automation tools and frameworks to increase testing efficiency.
- Working in a DevOps Microservices environment using tools such as Postman, JMeter, Azure DevOps for CI Testing.
- · Developed test scripts using C#, Selenium, Appium, Restsharp, specflow, Teststack.white, Nunit.

Cognizant

Hyderabad, India Test Engineer 4/2010 - 8/2014

- Testing Industrial Automation software and railway signaling hardware.
- Test case creation, Test execution, defects management and reporting using HP-QC.
- Design and develop test automation scripts using QTP.

## Education

## Biju Patnaik University of Technology **BTech Electronics and Communication**

2005 - 2009

## Courses

- \* AVEVA Leadership Foundation | AVEVA Management Development Program | Cognixia Azure 104 Administrator |
- \* STQC Certified Test Manager | Pluralsight Path Using the Scrum Framework